Abirami C

Counselling Psychologist

Contact

Address

Bangalore, India 560099

Phone

+918870009823

E-mail

abiramichittybabu@gmail.c om

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

 linkedin.com/in/abiramic854a691b3

Skills

- * Emotional Awareness
- * Family Counseling
- * Substance Abuse

Counseling

- * Psychological Assessment
- * Behavior Analysis
- * Employee Coaching

Certifications

- * Transactional Analysis PSG Tech (2016)
- * Functional English PSG CAS (2017)
- * Positive Psychology Fortis Healthcare (2021)
- * Cognitive Behavioural Therapy (CBT) - VRIKSH (2023)
- * Career Counselling Certificate - VRIKSH Psychological support service (2023)

I am a qualified Psychologist offering expertise in mental health, focused on assessing and measuring mental capabilities of individuals and providing appropriate solution and therapy. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet organizational requirements.

Education

2014-01 -	HSC
2015-01	Vidya Vikas Matric HSC - Karamadai Percentage: 93%
2015-01 -	B.SC Psychology
2018-01	PSG College of Arts and Science - Coimbatore Percentage: 66%
2019-01 - 2021-01	M.SC Counselling Psychology
	Madras University (dist) - Chennai
	Percentage: 70%
2012-01 - 2013-01	SSLC
	Vidya Vikas Matric HSC - Karamadai Percentage: 96.2%

Work History

2023-10 -Current

Psychologist

Ashok Leyland, Hosur

- Only Psychologist present for Hosur units covering over 10000+ employees across various categories of employee like Executives, Full time associates, 3rd Party labor's, Apprentices.
- Critically analyzed and interpreted reports related to addiction, self-harm and maladaptive behaviors across Plant 1, 2, 3.
- Conducted Weekly Training session for all sectors of employees
- Implemented sound, behavioral and psychological interventions to handle Apprentice and Btp students in age group ranging between 16 - 22 and Provided guidance and recommended coping mechanisms for youth dealing with difficult issues.
- Managed caseload of individual associates, couples, and their family therapy sessions.
- Counseled individuals and groups regarding problems such as stress, substance abuse and family situations to modify behavior to improve personal adjustment.
- Defined core problems and determined key strategies for investigating and remediating concerns.

2021-01 -	Freelancer
Current	Self
	 Personal counselling, Career counselling, Work life balance issues, Complex natures etc.
2023-07 -	Senior Executive
2023-09	 Wizklub Private Limited, Bangalore Analyzed and evaluated training effectiveness and program outcomes of Instructors -K3 Facilitated virtual blended learning sessions. Improved Instructor productivity by 30% using one to one connect and Mentoring Conducted needs assessments to identify gaps in performance and develop targeted learning solutions.
2023-04 -	School Counselor
2023-06	 Kendriya Vidyalaya CBSE School Handling students with Relationship issues, Parental conflict, Identity crisis, Addiction, Bullying , Peer pressure, Career confusions, Stress, OCD, Mobile addiction, Demotivation, etc Conducted Seminars for students and faculties.
2023-02 -	Psychologist
2023-05	 Grand World Elder Care Handled clients with Dementia, Phobia, depression, Anxiety, psychosis and other age related problem Administered stress coping mechanism, Cognitive Stimulation Therapy.
2021-07 - 2021-10	Trainee Psychologist
	 Srijan Counselling Service Counselled individuals and groups regarding problems such as stress, depression, anxiety, Interpersonal conflicts, substance abuse and family issues.
2017-03 -	Internship
2017-06	Krishna Nursing home
2016-03 -	Internship
2016-06	Nachiyaar Mind Care

• Organized employee orientation for new hires. • Organized Post Retirement Sessions for Associates whose service period is ending in 2023,2024.